# Rahul Baragur

734-819-0478 | baragurr@msu.edu |

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

I am a passionate sophomore student in Computer Science, aiming to leverage my skills and knowledge to land an internship position at your esteemed organization. I am highly motivated to gain experience during the internship to build a strong base for a successful career.

#### **EDUCATION**

Michigan State University Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Honors: Dean's List (Freshman Year)

Farmington High School High School Diploma

East Lansing, MI Aug. 2021 ~ Present GPA:3.71

Farmington, MI Sep. 2017 ~ May. 2021 GPA:3.94

## EXPERIENCE

Rush Chairman & Events Coordinator Kappa Sigma Fraternity Inc. – Delta Psi Chapter

Jun. 2021 ~ Present East Lansing, MI

- Held interviews and selected a committee to help assist me in my duties
- Coordinated daily meetings to hold budget discussions, event planning, member management etc.
- Utilized social media and networking to amass 100+ potential new members for the fraternity
- Consistently communicated with Kappa Sigma World Headquarters' representatives to discuss goals and tasks given to Delta Psi Chapter
- Presented and created various data sheets, budget lists, and planning sheets to HQ

## Doordash Delivery Driver Doordash

Feb. 2021 ~ Present Farmington Hills, MI

- Delivered consumables and groceries to various individuals throughout the city of Farmington Hills
- Acquired time-management skills by following and adhering to company policies

Grader Kumon

Jan. 2017 ~ Dec. 2018 Farmington Hills, MI

- Graded worksheets for every letter level for 15hours every week whilst being a full-time student
- Entered various sets of data in Microsoft Excel regarding each individual student
- Assisted students in teaching specific concepts in math & reading
- Managed other graders

# Simple Query Language | Python

Apr. 2023

- > Parses string by user as command and stores information in AVL tree database
- > Creates list of attributes and values from command such as length, width, and height
- Uses AVL Tree functionality to store data in Table object
- > Displays command into printed Table object
- > Similar functionality to SQL Language

LocoListen | Python

Jan. 2023

- > Worked with a team of four people during a hackathon to create branding, presentation, and software for a pseudo company called LocoListen
- > LocoListen uses location-based services from the Spotify API to show what people listening near the user's location on a map with datapoints
- > Allows users to input songs and playlists into to the worldwide map
- > Created a front-end web application using Streamlit API, Python, numpys, pandas, HTML, and CSS
- > Helped create a back-end that stored user's data into a SQL query and programmed functions that connected the front-end to back-end

Picture Decoder | C

Jan. 2023

- > Created a program that would take a C style string array of binary characters and turn it into a picture
- > Made two functions that would do an exclusive or and a circular left rotation on a line from the file to be decoded with a key

Piece & State Game | C++

Dec. 2022

> Board game where players have sets of game pieces fighting each other using four distinct classes/objects

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: Python, C++, C, HTML/CSS, ARM Assembly
- > Developer Tools: PyCharm, VSCode, Spyder, VIM, BASH/Terminal, Github, Cirsim, CLion
- Libraries: Matplotlib, Streamlit, numpys, pandas, Google Sheets DB, Spotify API

## COURSE WORK

# Completed:

- Introduction to Programming I Python
- > Introduction to Programing II C++
- Discrete Structures
- > Algorithms and Data Structures
- Computer Organization and Architecture
- Introduction to Engineering Design
- > Calculus 1, 2 & 3
- Physics 1,2 & Chemistry